I'm going to give you a glimpse as to why it works.
我将稍微解释下为何可行
Suppose we have two roller positions x0 and
假设有两个机器人位置 x0 和 x1
x1 and we know that 10-apart with some Gaussian noise,
并且相隔 10 个单位 具有一些高斯噪声
we know that the Gaussian noise and exploitation
我们知道预期高斯噪声
moves thr rightward position 10-off the leftward position,
使机器人从左侧位置向右移动 10 个单位
but there is some uncertainty.
但是有一些不确定性
When we talked about common filters,
当我们介绍卡尔曼滤波器时
we talked about Gaussians and this uncertainty might look as follows.
提到了高斯函数 这种不确定性可能如下所示
There is a constant, exponential in the expression that x1 minus x0 should relax to 10,
有一个指数常量 表达式为 (x1 - x0 - 10)2/σ2
but might deviate from it.
可能会偏离
This Gaussian constraint over here characterizes a constraint x1,
这里的高斯约束条件
x0 and wishes them to be exactly 10-apart.
限定了 x1 和 x0 之间的关系 希望它们正好相隔 10
The Gaussian is maximum with this equation is fulfilled,
满足这个方程式时 高斯函数是最大值
but if the residual is not equals zero,
但是如果余数不等于 0
there's still a probability associated with it.
依然有与其相关的概率
Let's now model a second motion.
我们现在建模第二个运动
Say x2 is five apart.
假设 x2 与 x1 相隔 5 个单位
We now get an even bigger Gaussian relative to the very first one,
现在相对于第一个位置的高斯值更高
but the local constraint over here reads just like the constraint over there.
但是这里的局部约束条件和这里的约束条件一样
So, let me just write it down.
我写下来
x2 minus x1 minus five square over sigma square.
(x2 - x1 - 5)2/σ2
Now, the total probability of
这里的整个概率是
this entire thing over here is the product of these two things.
这两项的积
If we want to maximize the product,
如果要最大化积
we can play a number of interesting tricks.
可以采用多个有趣的技巧
First, the constant has no bearing on the maximum,
首先 常量对最大值没有影响
just on the absolute value.
只是对绝对值有影响
So, if we want to find the best values for x0 and x1 and so on,
因此 如果我们想算出 x0 和 x1 等的最佳值
we can drop the constant.
可以删掉常量
Secondly, we can drop the
其次 如果要将积变成加法
exponential if we're willing to turn the product into an addition,
可以删掉指数
and remember, we edit things in omega and in sigma, that's why.
因为我们修改的是 Ω 和 σ 中的量
And finally, we can actually drop the minus a half.
最后 可以删掉 -1/2
Turns out it also plays no role in the maximization of this expression.
它对最大化此表达式也没影响
So, it turns out what you added,
实际上 你添加了
where constraints just like these and you even
像这样的约束条件
added them as a certain strength of one over sigma square.
甚至添加为 1/σ2
In particular, if you really believe that a constraint is true,
尤其是 如果你真的认为某个约束条件为真
you should add a larger value in this matrix over here and on the right side,
应该在这个矩阵中添加更大的值
you should multiply the right constraint with an even larger value.
在右侧 应该使右侧约束条件与更大的值相乘
For definitely, taking the expression like this and multiplying the sigma square,
将这样的表达式与 σ2 相乘
you get something of this nature over here where one over
得出这样的方程
sigma regulates how confident you are for a small sigma,
1/σ 规定了你对小 σ 的信心程度
one over sigma becomes large,
当 σ 变大时
so five is much larger than one.
5 比 1 大很多
That means you have much more confidence.
表明你更有信心
Let's go back to the code and modify the code.
我们回到代码部分并修改代码
So, the last measurement has a really high confidence.
使最后一个测量项置信水平很高
So, I wanted to multiply the last measurement between
请在你的代码中将 x2 和地标之间的测量值
x2 and our landmark with the factor of five, in your code.
与因子 5 相乘